Guide to the Eardley-Wilmot Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence
  - "P"
    - Parr, Samuel, 1747-1825. 2 ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1793 Jun (Box 3, Folder 108)
      Letters discuss the French clergy and the French Revolution and give Parr's opinions on both matters.
    - Parry, Charles Henry, 1779-1860. 2 ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1810 Apr (Box 3, Folder 109)
      On Wilmot's health, symptoms and remedies.
    - Perceval, Spencer, 1762-1812. Letter (copy) to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1807 Apr (Box 3, Folder 110)
      About the Lansdowne Manuscript collection and its purchase by the British Museum.
    - Phillips, John. ALS to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1806 Sep (Box 3, Folder 111)
      Thanks Wilmot for a copy of his books and seeks to obtain a political appointment.
    - Philo-Charitos, pseud. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1793 Jul (Box 3, Folder 112)
      Thanks Wilmot for his work to aid French exiled clergy and includes a donation.
    - Pitcairn, David, 1749-1809. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1806 Jun (Box 3, Folder 113)
      On Wilmot's health.
    - Pitt, William, 1759-1806. 3 ALS (signatures cut) to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1788 Dec-1793 Jan (Box 3, Folder 114)
      First letter requests Wilmot's attendance in Commons and the third deals with the proposed appointment by Wilmot to Public Office of a certain Mr. Marsh.
    - Planta, Joseph, 1744-1827. 19 ALS and 1 letter to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1798 Aug-1807 Dec (Box 3, Folder 115)
      Letters mostly deal with the sale of the Burleigh and Lansdowne Collections.
    - Plumer, Thomas, 1753-1824. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1802 Nov (Box 3, Folder 116)
      Thanks Wilmot for a copy of his book.
    - Porteus, Beilby, Bp. of London, 1731-1808. 2 ALS to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1793 May, Nov (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Praed, William Mackworth. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 118)
      Thanks Wilmot for a copy of his book. Praed is the father of William Mackworth Praed, the poet.
    - Price, John, 1734-1813. 4 ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1794 Jan-1809 Oct (Box 3, Folder 119)
      On several Oliver Cromwell letters.
  - "R"
    - "R" general, 1792-1807 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Roberts, Thomas. ALS to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1808 Oct (Box 3, Folder 121)
      Discusses the deteriorating physical condition of Bruce Castle.
    - Roberts, William, 1767-1849. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1803 Nov (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Romilly, Sir Samuel, 1757-1818. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1810 Dec (Box 3, Folder 123)
      About Peter Mark Roget.
    - Rooke, Sir Giles, 1743-1808. ALS and 1 AL to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1794 Jan, 1797? (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Rose, [George, 1744-1818]? ALS (signature cut) to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1793 Apr (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Ross, James. 11 ALS to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1809 Jun-Oct (Box 3, Folder 126)
      Letters discuss Bishop Hough of Worcester and deal mostly with engravings and sculpture of the Bishop. Ross was apparently an artist commissioned by Wilmot.
    - Rough, William, d. 1838. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1810 Oct (Box 3, Folder 127)
      Discusses a private law case.
    - Routh, Martin John, 1755-1854. 2 ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1809 Sep, Oct (Box 3, Folder 128)
      With copy of Eardley-Wilmot's reply.
  - "S"
    - "S" general, 1776-1809 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Sargent, John, d. 1831. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1802 Nov (Box 3, Folder 130)
      Thanks Wilmot for a copy of his father's memoirs.
    - Sharp, Granville, 1735-1813. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1803 Feb (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Sperling, Henry P. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1806 Mar (Box 3, Folder 132)
      On the economic and political problems of an unnamed parish.
    - Stevenson, Seth William, 1784-1853. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1807 Mar (Box 3, Folder 133)
      Letter discusses details of publishing a work by Wilmot.
    - Stevenson, William, 1741-1821. 3 ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1806 Aug-1809 Jun (Box 3, Folder 134)
      Letters deal with political events pertaining mostly to local Parliamentary elections.
    - Stover, John. 2 ALS to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1809 Nov-Dec (Box 3, Folder 135)
      Letter discusses John Hough, Bp. of Worcester, and includes a partial family tree.
    - Strahan, George, 1744-1824? ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1793 Jan (Box 3, Folder 136)
      Letter discusses an Oliver Cromwell letter. Strahan describes Cromwell as having "rendered himself immortal, tho' it be only by Pre-eminence in Villany."
    - Sutton, Thomas. ALS to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1806 Dec (Box 3, Folder 137)
      Letter concerns the candidacy of a friend of Wilmot's for a Cadetship at the Royal Academy at Woolwich[?].
  - "T"
    - "T" general, 1803 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Trevor, John Hampden, 1749-1824. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1808 May (Box 3, Folder 139)
      Letter deals with the poor financial condition of a French refugee and Wilmot is asked for help.
  - "W"
    - "W" general, 1794-1809 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Wakefield, Priscilla, 1751-1832. ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, [after 1805] (Box 3, Folder 141)
      Thanks Wilmot for the use of his personal library.
    - Warren, Dawson. ALS to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1807 Sep (Box 3, Folder 142)
      Letter deals with a local problem concerning "mirth and jollity among the lower classes" and "licentious meetings of the Rich."
    - Warren, John Borlase, 1753-1822. 4 ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot and 1 ALS from Lady Warren, 1794 Jan-1809 Apr (Box 3, Folder 143)
      The last letters speak of some of the logistical problems which the British Army faced.
    - Wentworth, John to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1803 May 23 (Box 3, Folder 144)
      ALS expressing thanks for Eardley- Wilmot's gift to and interest in King's College in Halifax, Nova Scotia.
    - Wilberforce, William, 1759-1833. ALS (signature removed) to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1802 Nov (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Wilmot, Ann. ALS to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1808 Feb (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Wilmot, Edward
      - 7 ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1782 Oct-1805 Nov (Box 3, Folder 147)
        Letters discuss personal matters. One letter (1784 Jun 4) proposes several forms of taxation which will not greatly bother the poor.
      - 3 ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1806 Feb-Aug (Box 3, Folder 148)
        On family financial matters.
    - Wilmot, Emma. ALS to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1810 Dec (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Wilmot, Lucy. 3 ALS to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1809 Jan-1810 Dec (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Wilmot, Martha. 33 ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1803 Oct-1810 Nov (Box 3, Folder 151)
      Letters mostly discuss personal and financial matters. There are a few references to the Napoleonic Wars and to Russia's internal political affairs.
    - Wilmot, Robert. 11 ALS to John Eardley-Wilmot, 1800 Sep-1807 Dec (Box 3, Folder 152)
      Letters discuss personal matters and Sir John Eardley-Wilmot's memoirs.
    - Windham, W[illiam, 1750-1810]? ALS (signature removed) to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1793 Aug (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Wren, Matt. 4 ALS to John Eardley- Wilmot, 1768 Jan-1770 Jan (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - "Y"
    - "Y" general, [n.y.] May 27 (Box 3, Folder 155)
- Other Papers, 1795-1809, n.d.
  - Unidentified letter copies and letter fragments, some in French, 1795-1809, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - Personal papers of John Eardley-Wilmot, 1767-1808, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 157)
    Includes certificate of his call to the Bar; manuscript (incomplete) of "A Letter to the Publick for the P. Advertiser"; printed copy of a commentary on a proposed monument for "Mr. Howard"; and bills and receipts.
  - "Indices of letters" (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Biographical and bibliographical information on John Eardley-Wilmot, 1912, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - "The Effects of the Preliminaries of the American Revolution on the Career of Sir John Eardley Wilmot", typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 160)